Okay. We're gonna call to order the town of Andover Board of Selectmen
special meeting budget workshop for 02/28/2022.
And we're gonna start with the pledge of allegiance.
I pledge allegiance To the flag. To the flag of The United States Of America to
the republic for which it stands,
one nation
under the law, individual,
liberty,
justice for Alright.
>> We had started with number two, public speak.
So we're gonna go to Erin Boris.
>> I'm all set. Thank you. Alright. Diane Choquette.
I'm all set. Thanks.
>> Alright. We're good to go.
So
our budget workshop for fiscal twenty twenty two, twenty twenty three.
Did everyone have a chance to review the document,
the chair you put out?
I'm
thinking it came over today.
Say that again, Eric? Did it come over today?
>> Yes. I think so. I've been home all day. So I came over on Saturday, actually. Saturday morning.
Okay.
>> So I I'm assuming from my review
of it is basically everything that we had agreed upon.
There's some
Yes, that's correct. Some questions like, where did the salt go?
Like, are we doing something different with salt? Am I missing it?
>> Also, looks like this, the school number is still 100,000
below what we're currently looking at, so.
Okay.
>> Sorry to interrupt. My internet
kind of went a little weird. Did we do public speak already?
Yeah, meeting's over.
It's
close. It's close. You
missed it.
>> All right. And then your next question was you're looking at
the spreadsheet that Sherry sent, right? Right.
>> The school
budget reflects
what is currently
being brought to the Board of Education for their approval.
>> That's the current proposal number? Yes.
Okay. I thought that had gone up because of the outplacement.
My apologies.
>> Yeah, it was lower, and
then we put the outplacement in there. So
what we initially had in there was a replacement of 3%.
Yep. You asked that I put the number
that it is. So the 4122
is the current op? Yes.
>> Perfect. I
just want to make sure we weren't missing that in. No, no, that's what's going before the Board of Ed on March 2.
Okay,
alright.
Jeff, you had a question on
salt?
>> To answer your question, the salt line
went away, and it's in the
supplies
line.
Yeah. Just because the chart of accounts has changed a little bit. So, it's still in
there.
There's still $60,000
roughly allocated towards salt.
It's just not under the salt line item. It's under
the winter snow removal supplies
line item.
>> So
what's under that line item? Sand and salts and
dry mix?
I can't tell you exactly.
>> Yeah. I have to check it myself. So
what all is in there, I don't know. I have to double check.
Can you tell us what line it is currently?
It's line
303642.
Yeah.
Correct.
>> So
we need to move that comment up.
Anyway, I mean, those
Sherry, those errors,
like, where something doesn't work, we've got to we should fix those,
>> You know, at least the final, are you talking about the ones in the final column?
Yeah. Yeah. And that's, that I'll do after
tonight when you approve the budget for that says
Board of Selectmen approved requests.
If you make any changes, I'm not sure at this point, but if it stays as is, then I will
address the Board of Finance approved request columns,
and I'll make sure that that
gets fixed
before moving forward.
Okay.
You said it was you said it was 03/2003?
03/2003
and June.
I'm under snow removal budget.
>> Yeah. I'm looking.
I mean, it it makes sense. I mean but this goes into
purging our chart of accounts even further. If we're gonna do things like this, just keep
getting rid of accounts.
>> I I don't intend to at this point, to be honest with you. I
I've made all the changes that I think
the auditor will be agreeable upon,
And I hope to just move forward with this chart of accounts
>> here on in. Right. But I think what he's saying is that this,
because there's legacy items from before we changed the chart of accounts,
next year, when we have two years of data with this chart of accounts,
we won't show all those lines that are basically zeroed out and there's nothing in there. Correct. Absolutely.
Yeah.
Not just this year, since we have both the new chart of accounts and the old chart of accounts represented here,
you can see what the total was,
they're both displayed.
Right. So I get that this month.
>> I'd like to see some minor changes if we're going to leave it like this though,
so that residents and board members know where things are. So for instance, instead of just saying
supplies,
let's
label it sand salt supplies.
I would put it over in the notes.
>> Why can't we put it on the, why can't we put it in the name of the thing?
>> You could,
then, and
then what you're sitting there doing is, oh, what happens when it's not saying it's all?
>> There's other things I'm sure that are in there.
Well,
>> prior to, prior to the change up,
it looks like we had, what,
$6,000
in there last year.
Correct. And I I guess that's my concern is like literally the biggest part of it is sand and salt. So
let's and those are things as a that are our commodity that we need to those are big things that we want to be tracking.
Know? And that goes into whether we're putting bids out for sand and salt or whether we're following a state bid or things like that. I think those are important. I
would like I would like to at the very least see the name change please.
Well, okay. Why why why
>> I don't have a problem with that. Wait a second.
>> Just put the salt number in the salt line. It's really not that hard. Well, that make more sense to me. I mean, I would agree that, but it I understand what she's trying to do with purging. You know, that purge is two lines right there if you do that. Listen.
>> I don't sand sand is zero. Right, Eric? You don't buy in sand, right?
We occasionally buy some sand. Don't buy We
>> have leftover. We have leftover because what we we had a couple of light years and so we encouraged.
We encourage public works to buy as much sand as they get their hands on. So to use up the budget, you know, and you know, you're always commodities never go down there, so we bought as much as we could, so we stockpiled.
>> I mean the sand, the salt number is $58,000
I personally would have no problem with you needing salt,
but I don't know why you would want to consolidate
that too. Mean there's other things I would consolidate and I would get rid of line items that one might not be one I would get rid of but if you're going to I understand where agents come and put supplies sand and salt in the name but
leave salt.
>> That was the recommendation from the auditor, and I'm just I was just going along with what he recommended.
Yep. We do. That's all.
If you want me to put it back, I'll put it back.
>> He's not gonna get really mad at one line item.
No. Mean, really You
have a contract that when you buy the salt, Eric, am I not wrong? You have one contract or basically it's a state contract, you're going out and when you find it, you pay the state rate, right?
>> At
the moment, we have two contracts going because we buy both treated and untreated salt.
Okay. And are they at the state contract rate?
>> One of them is the state contract rate.
One of them is a rate we got directly from the vendor later in the year when it looked like they had sufficient stockpiles.
They gave us a much better deal than we asked Turns
>> out salt is more complicated than any of us guessed.
>> Yeah. Two two whole invoices.
Yeah. But $58 worth of two whole invoices. That's a lot of money. I won't disagree with that. Yeah. A lot of money. Leave it in this online item. I mean, heck it's
>> Alright. Yeah. So,
are we moving sand into the supply line item? Are we good with that? Sure. Go ahead.
Alright, so you get to get rid of one, Jerry.
Can put sand in the supply, but put sand and
supplies
and then keep salt separately.
Okay,
will do. Thank you. So
>> are there any other questions on any of the other items?
>> What
What do we have left to make decisions
on tonight?
>> I thought it was just the overall budget passing the whole thing up. Correct.
>> Alright, so this reflects all the changes we made last
week to pay.
Yes,
yes, absolutely.
>> Eric, on this last one, are you good with it?
Yeah. I'm good with it.
Okay.
>> How's everyone feel about it? I mean, we're at
33 mills give or take?
>> Gotta fix those things.
I don't really care about the mill rate.
I care about
the overall increase.
Oh, where is the totals for this whole thing?
I don't even have it on the revenue side, but
>> Totals for the whole So on the first page,
under department totals,
below that is budget totals.
It lists the total, the general budget, and then the general budget minus capital funds.
What page is that?
First page?
First page.
It's nine sixty eight.
Yeah.
Yep.
68.
>> So we have a $512,000
increase.
Okay.
So are we all good passing that number on to the board of finance?
4.12%
increase
in total.
Doesn't seem right.
Why does that seem right?
>> Think it's too low, too high? What do you think it's No, I was saying the number doesn't sound right. The percentage, the percentage increase doesn't seem.
Why?
>> This doesn't seem right in my mind, Eric. I'm sorry. Okay.
Okay.
>> I know what he's saying.
I'm just trying to figure out where it is in the sheet.
Basically
>> it breaks down to this. The town budget increases 10.67%,
which is 36
$3,363,000
AES increases 5.65%,
which is 2 and $20,000
RAM budget decreases 1.4%
or $71,000
which totals up to
$512,000
in overall spending increase.
>> All right, so
here's a question,
just so we all know where our numbers are coming from.
What are our big increases? Because we're responsible to explain this to the public.
Public
>> works is one of the big ones, right? So, first of all, capital spending increases $195,000
That's the biggest single increase on the town budget side.
Then How much was that? 190
>> which 5,000
is 22%.
That's the biggest, by far the biggest increase.
Yep.
>> Okay. And then all the other town spending increases $170,000
of which
$70,000
roughly is the cost, a little over 70,000
is the cost of the additional employee at Public Works.
And $20,000
of that is the cost of the temp summer hire at Public Works.
And about $25,000
is increased spending at public works
for building maintenance and stuff like that.
The
total public works increase is 145,351.
Yeah. That's roughly
right.
Yep.
>> I liked your breakdown, Eric. Thank you. What was your, what was your increase, Jeff? One what? 145,351.
>> 115.
So everything else is, is, is
under, under $10,000
>> every other department. Well, mean, based on his highlight numbers, then there's another 20 ks somewhere in public works, because
he said 20,
for the part time hire, 77 for the
full timer, and 25 for building.
>> That still leaves us 20 ks somewhere else in public works. Yeah, a big chunk of that is, you know, we've been consistently
underfunding,
>> you know, both the public works equipment line item. Oh, yeah. Maintenance equipment. That's right. We discussed this. Right. So sorry. That's where most of that is. Okay. Yep. Yep. Yep. So if you go through and you look at other departments or line items that have increased
over $10,000
so you have the town garage,
there was a $17,745
increase?
>> I mean, but you know, so when we talk about
a budget with several 100 lines in it, but really it comes down to this is where that this is where it is. I mean, it's
give or take,
you know, you know, give or take three big, three big lines, you know, or three big. But remember
>> too, that part of the reason why this doesn't look a lot worse than it does
is
the fact that one,
we've retired the bond at AES,
which nets the town $93,000
And we have also paid off the loader, which nets the town
$32,000
32,000 Yeah. Right.
>> Right.
So,
are increasing spending in this budget
pretty significantly
when you take out those two factors. The question
>> becomes,
Is this following what we have talked about for the last three or four years?
Is this going in the direction that we said we wanted the town to go?
You know, are we are we bringing
everything in line with what we know is a functioning.
Town hall a functioning public works.
And getting the town back to where it needs to be,
and is this,
I think the other question I think the question that the residents are going to ask us is,
is this it? Are we finally there? Is this the last swath of getting things sort of ironed out on a bigger budget scale?
I mean, I think this puts us pretty much where we need to be with public works.
It's not perfect for capital spending, but I think it's functional.
We've certainly got the salaries, I think, lined up. I don't know that there's much, I mean, there may be some tweaks, but I don't know that there's a lot more coming
at all that I can think of that we need to be asking about.
I mean, anyone else disagree with that? Is there something else
that we've completely overlooked? I mean, I know we could Well,
>> I just I think one thing we ought to highlight in this whole budget is the the the fact of the matter that we can basic we're basically gonna pay for the community center,
and that money that we would have had to raise through a bond would have been substantial as well. So we're actually getting to expand public works,
meet the needs of the school, and meet the needs of the town, and get a community center on top of this for, you know, pretty much a modest increase. It's not it's not anything I would think that would be,
you know, out of realm of, you know, with the with the current inflation and everything going on. I mean, you you know, like the school went up, fuel costs went up. Right. It's just it's the nature of the beast, unfortunately.
>> But I think the other thing too is I I think I I I'm okay with it because
the number one thing we have been hearing for the last two years is public works, public works, public works.
Why aren't you addressing my road? Why aren't we fixing the potholes here? Why aren't we fixing the potholes there?
So,
you know,
so we're trying to put our money where our mouth is and
address those issues, but it takes money. It can't just be done for free.
>> The 4.12%
is accurate.
So It is. The math is right.
Okay. That's the number. Yeah. 4.2.
Okay.
So 4.1 And
>> I think the other thing you do have to keep in mind is
last year, essentially the budget
for the town and the school was flat.
Right. So, when you put it in that perspective,
you know, you can basically say,
you know, part of what we're doing is making up for the fact that we ended up with a completely flat budget last year.
>> Wasn't that, Roy? It almost was the last two years.
>> No, not two years. The year before, we definitely had an increase.
But
part of the issue last year was we were just coming off of that period
where we had excess unexpended fund balance to burn.
And the farther we get, the less of that there is.
You know,
that's what we've been using to offset some of the bigger expenses.
>> So in our revenue this year, have $100,000
of
unused total balance we're using.
>> Yeah, that was the, what the auditor suggested we could use as a number prior to getting the final audit complete.
Are
>> we, where are we at with the audit? I mean, I thought that we were on track to get this audit before this budget
>> got locked up. I put a call into him and I
yeah. He's supposed to call me back.
I would assume that he's gonna talk to me tomorrow because
he should have had everything done today.
>> And so when were you expecting it, Sherry? Did he give you a time frame?
>> Well, he took an extension to February 28.
So here we are. Now
>> if he puts in another extension, don't we have to sign it?
>> Yeah, we have to approve it. And he hasn't come back for for a signature? Not yet, but tomorrow morning I'm
gonna give him
definitely a call if he hasn't returned my call.
Okay.
And why do we have an extension?
>> Did I miss something? Because anytime you go past That's done.
If you start going into the new year and your audit's not ready, you have to get an extension. I think they run them on thirty days. Right? Right.
So
Correct.
And you know, mean, listen,
the problem is we're small towns. We end up on the bottom of everybody's pile. So I don't know that we're ever going to get an audit done in January unless our town triples in size, but
in the meantime,
you know, they've been pretty good to us.
>> And why do, why do small towns get bumped down to the bottom? Because our budget to do an audit's like $33,000
>> and, you know, you talk about somebody like Hebron or
Coventry,
you know, they're, they're three times that.
So
>> We have been slowly moving up the pecking order. Yeah. I mean, it's only taken seven years, but When they took us on as a client originally,
they were pretty clear that it was going to be delayed every year
because
they had more than they could accomplish
in the fiscal year.
Now,
last year, the auditor said he thought they had enough
of their clients
had dropped off that he thought they could get us done a lot more timely.
That hasn't really worked out.
And I'm not overly happy about it. It's always nice to go into budget season with a completed audit.
>> For
perspective, though, Paula, we've put this out to bid and
we got three bids each time we did it basically.
One of them was unqualified.
Like literally there are news stories about the horrors of this person being an auditor.
One person was out of the one group was out of Maine.
Not a
great situation either.
And then this, you know, group,
so
they were not the cheapest,
but at least they had a, you know, they, they had a decent reputation in Connecticut and they were, they're willing to work with us. Cause at the time we were looking,
we were like,
you know, we, we basically had had multiple audits and multiple treasurers come through, you know, in several years. That just were horrible.
>> I mean,
they are a very good firm I've worked with them before.
>> Right. In another district. They known quantity versus some of these like,
we had literally someone that was in Northern Maine that was going to,
you know, send someone down to take all of our stuff and then go back to Maine with it.
Yeah.
Okay. Not ideal.
>> One other thing that we're we're going to have slightly increased maintenance costs at the Veterans Park.
Is that in the budget?
>> I don't think that's changed at all on the budget. Well isn't are you talking about since the accident? I thought we were putting an insurance claim in. No, no I'm talking about you know ongoing
>> maintenance you know fertilizer,
lime, that kind of He's talking for the ball field. Care of the we're going to be taking care of the Veterans Park also.
Did
>> we talk about this? I'm I'm. That's the first time I'm hearing of it. First of hearing that.
Myself.
Scott, can you I know that
they're going to be mowing it for free.
>> Okay.
I'm not expecting them to pay for all the fertilizer and everything else to keep the grass up. Well, can you? Can we expect them to pay for it so that we don't have to play with this budget anymore?
I mean, do we have a number? Do we have a?
Well, I don't.
Scott, do you have any more information on that? 313420
maybe?
$313?
>> No. I don't I don't have any information yet. We've we haven't done it yet.
Adrian's first time.
>> I mean to pay for it is that what you guys are getting at or what? No, I think we're trying to understand what kind of number we need to plug in here.
Are we pulling it out of the air or do we do you have a not? I mean, are we are we a thousand dollars? Are we
$500
>> are we 5. Would say that 500 or less would probably do it.
What
line item should it go in Scott.
Maybe mowing ground care.
Can you give us the
It's
Row511.
313420.
>> Row511?
Yeah.
Yep.
Jeff, are you all right?
Mr. McGuire? You
do not sound good.
No, because of the mask mandate, I caught COVID.
>> Did you really catch COVID? I did.
Sorry to hear that. I'm glad to see you're on your feet though.
>> I'll stop by with some chicken soup for you, Mr. McGuire.
No. You're all set, Paul. I appreciate it, though.
He's a meatatarian. He doesn't eat chicken soup.
>> I ate I had made my own soup today. I am capable.
Good job.
>> That's probably why he sounds like that, because he made his own chicken soup.
Alright. So, we have
$20,000
approved in that line.
21.
21. 21,000.
>> So we went up, we went up a thousand dollars.
>> Yeah. I meant previously. So we went up a thousand.
I'm gonna ask why.
So, did that not encompass that, Eric?
>> I mean, you know, you're springing this on me now that we suddenly want to do extra stuff at the monument.
>> I mean, I know Jerry asked me- It's not the vet, not, no, He's talking
about the field,
Veterans Field.
No, he's actually talking about the memorial.
>> No, he's talking about the memorial,
Scott. Am I correct? Yeah.
Mean, Jerry
went to you guys earlier this year and told you that he wanted $20,000
a year and that he would maintain that.
But it didn't sound like you guys wanted to entertain that.
I have not adjusted the budget for any of that.
If you decide you want to add extra money into it for something specific,
then
so be it. The only thing I was accounting for is the fact that we now have one extra sprinkler system we got to blow out.
And we have, we're going to have costs associated with that.
Right.
>> Okay. I ask a question on that line item, Eric, or Sherry. Like, currently, we only have $5,000
expended.
Is the contract with Hebron front
loaded? I mean, do they charge us all in April?
When do they charge us? I don't know. I
haven't gone through that cycle yet.
>> Well, does 20 ks cover that contract? Is that what we're saying?
>> Yeah, we've been able to cover it. We went over the year before
due to expenses
dealing with the sprinkler system.
But 20,000 should cover
the maintenance costs for that field
and the mowing costs
associated with Andover Landscaping.
>> So, let's
let's either leave the $21,000
in there and see where we end up this year.
Or Scott, if you want, do you want us to add a thousand dollars to this? And would you like to propose that?
What makes sense for, for what you're thinking,
>> I don't, I don't think we need a thousand dollars.
>> I don't think that that's. Well, I mean, let's, I'm just gonna say what everyone's not saying is that we need a number associated with that
park so that this doesn't turn into
a $20,000
expense.
>> It's not Adrian. Last year I did it was less than a $100.
>> No, I'm just saying if we're, you know, if Jerry came to us and said he was asking for 20 But Jerry, yeah, but that's, it's
>> just maintenance taking care of the grass,
fertilizing it, liming it.
That's all. It's not
going to cost a lot of money.
>> Okay, so propose what you want then so we can move on. I would I propose,
>> know, dollars 500 should be enough to take care of that part of it.
Okay, seconded.
Alright. Further discussion?
All those in favor?
>> Aye. Aye.
So we're increasing that line item from 21,000
to $21.05.
>> Mr. Murray, would you like to vote on that?
I am and I. Thank you. You're welcome. So, Sherry, if you'll make that $21,500.
Okay.
I will.
>> Okay.
Is there anything else that anyone would like to bring up?
>> No, I think we're kind of,
think we're kind of there.
I didn't get a chance to open your workbook yet, Eric.
Is that your budget draft book? Is that pretty much reviewing the things that we were talking about as far as the expense?
You have a highlight Did
you put a highlight area in there?
What do you mean by a highlight area? Well, so for instance, as we talked about, you know, we basically have,
you know, we had capital, we had a town wide, we had public works. Are the three big drivers. Did you do like an over an overall?
To explain what the drivers were?
Yes.
>> I'm asking because again, I'm telling you I did not get a chance to review it today, but between getting home and
Yeah, I said yes.
>> Okay.
And unfortunately, it's still not loading.
I get a spinning No, that, that is,
>> the text of the budget document could be addressed even after us. When are you planning on giving this to
board of finance, Eric?
Once we approve it? Tomorrow. Tonight. Yeah. Tomorrow, probably.
>> Okay.
Since
our first budget meeting is in two days,
it's gonna have to go to them tomorrow.
>> Okay.
I went through it, Adrian. I didn't have a problem.
And I also read it, Adrian.
Okay. This document.
>> So basically,
we're we have a
proposed budget to send to the Board of Finance of $12,939,892
So,
>> go ahead. Anybody got any issues with it? No, so my only question is how do we wanna handle,
do we want to
do a separate
proposal for the funds, American Cares Act funds for the community center?
>> Sure, why don't we do two motions? One to approve the entire budget and one to utilize
those funds for the Community Center.
Okay.
All right,
so
let's make a motion on the overall budget or actually make a motion on the use of the CARES Act funds.
>> Yeah, so I make a motion that we use the
American CARES Act funds for the funding of an Andover community center
not to exceed $1,000,000
I'll second that.
Okay.
Further discussion on that issue?
>> Sure. Why are you gonna spend the whole million on that when you've got $450,000
sitting in
a multi use building fund specifically for that?
Well,
allocate one half of the American Cares Act funds for that.
Well, for keep the remainder for other things.
Well,
>> I.
There's a couple issues there one is
do we build a building and then not staff it after the fact.
Because that's one of the issues that we have is that you know we we really have been struggling to staff our Community resources,
you know we know we woefully understaffed them,
you know we have a
you know we have.
Coordinators that you know do a lot of things that are not getting paid now, and we know that's not going to continue forever, You
know
so
step one step two I think once the once the building is done and we start talking about putting things in the building,
you know the building cost does not include
you know,
maybe some of the things that we need in the building to make it more functional. Right. I. E. Electronics,
chairs,
>> all that wonderful stuff. Right. And the building cost may not include all the parking changes.
>> Yeah. That may be a separate issue as well,
after the fact.
We have some after the fact issues that we may have to deal with.
Okay.
You have You've answered your own question.
>> Do you have any other specific areas also? And this is one of the drivers. Is it, do you have any other specific areas that we can spend that funds on? We can't use it for trees. We can't use it for roadwork.
>> Well, we don't know that yet. We won't know that until such time
as the auditor completes the audit and gives us the report
of year to year comparables so we know how much of it
you know, falls under that category and how much of it can be used to make up lost revenue.
>> The answer to that is we don't know that. You can't use it to make up lost revenue. That was made very clear.
How, Eric?
>> I'm not going to risk a talent. I'm just going say it right now. I'm not going to risk a talent audit to try to work in a gray area and be like, you know,
>> some of these other towns that are getting audited because of that. Well, I, I would just ask the question, how long do we have to spend those dollars?
Two years plus.
>> Okay.
So
Eric, we'll know at the end of our audit what we can potentially spend on if there's any other options?
Correct.
>> Okay.
And
Well, I mean, I'm still trying to go ahead. I have no I have no problem with
sitting there saying we want to allocate it all to the community center.
>> Right. We
also know that in general
the, the other issue here is that in general,
if we we we approve a certain amount of money and then we end up short on the building, because
the one issue we run into is, we have to stay under 1,000,000 if we go over 1,000,000.
Will end up in a Davis bacon territory, and we will will need that extra 400 ks just to just to just to complete it.
So.
And this is why that's kind of what happened with the soccer fields remember.
You know. The soccer field.
>> You remember when you build on the field and your numbers kept climbing?
Because it became a union project?
The soccer field was a $400,000
project. Right. Right.
Never changed, Adrian.
>> When
they, from the initial, from the initial estimate, it didn't change? A little bit. A little $5,000
>> or something maybe? No, it's more than that. No. I mean, only major change was when the town
contemplated
whether they wanted, because there was only enough money to build a truncated field.
If the town had elected to build a regular regulation
size soccer field, it would have been a considerably more expensive endeavor.
That is a regulation soccer field. It is.
>> No, the one that's down there now.
But when we had the plans to put it behind
the elementary school,
The deciding factor between a full size field
and
a condensed field
the amount of fill that had to be brought in.
And since the town wasn't willing to spend any of their own money,
you know, the hard cap
>> wasn't gonna allow you to build anything more than a truncated field. So that was the cost shift when it went to the other field. It got bigger.
I mean, I'm just confused. Like, it it you know, that Well, anyways, look, the bottom line is the, the state has, the state has a certain figure for each project.
Yeah. And for a, for a new construction,
the cap is a million dollars. We, our goal is to stay under 1,000,000. Okay. So, so we're going to utilize
>> the CARES Act fund to keep the project, to build the building.
Right.
You know, under a million dollars.
>> Exactly.
Okay.
And then we may use the, the other funds to do some of the build out of,
you know, like, you know, other types of things that will make that building more functional for different, for different events. Understood.
>> So does anybody have a problem with that? It's already been seconded.
Does anyone want to have any further discussion on this?
No? So
all those in favor of the motion?
Aye.
Aye. Okay.
>> All right. Now if someone can make a motion on the overall budget.
>> I'll make a motion that we
accept
the budget presented tonight
by the,
town treasurer.
You want the number?
>> Sure.
Alright. Hang on. 12939800.
392.
No. We 800 and We've 90
just passed a motion to add $500
to Fielding. So, well, we Yeah.
>> Sorry.
My bad. No problem. I still have it in don't edit mode. I got it.
I'll second that.
>> Okay. So $12,000,939.39000.
500 and or sorry, you had 510, so 892.
>> 892.
Perfect. Right. Okay. And Scott, you seconded that. Right.
Okay. Further discussion?
All those in favor?
Aye. Aye.
Jeff Murray? Aye.
>> Okay.
Okay.
So,
I think we're actually done. Is there anything else? Well, one other thing we need to do before we leave our meeting,
we have to,
schedule another special meeting
sometime this week for two issues one is the BAA we have to appoint
an alternate
and on this meeting I'd like to actually
have an employee
have it put on the agenda
to discuss an employee matter
related to mister Anderson.
Alright.
So we have to do the the BAA
one before the twelfth. So does anyone have time? This shouldn't be a very long meeting.
I know no one wants to have any more meetings, but Thursday?
Wednesday?
>> What works for you? Wednesday, I've got board of education, and Thursday, have plans already.
K.
Tomorrow Adrian,
>> what time are your plans? Can we sneak it in before that or no?
>> No, I've got a meeting at 05:00 and it's probably gonna be two hours, two and a half. So. On Wednesday?
Thursday. I've got a meeting on Wednesday for board of education for their budget.
Are you going to my birthday party on Wednesday?
>> No, unless it's at the board of education. No.
God's birthday.
That's correct.
>> Okay. Birthday. We have to sing. That means we gotta sing tonight. No. Not today. Regular meeting. No. No. No. No.
>> We only have we we have very few people here, so we're good. You want, I can do, can anyone do tomorrow night?
That is my anniversary.
So.
Oh, anniversary.
Anniversary.
>> Happy Happy anniversary. That mean we have to sing happy anniversary?
Yes.
>> K.
Can we do it Monday then?
That would give us well, actually, if I remember Georgia's
email,
I think she needed to get this done.
>> Can we do we have people for the appointment already?
There's two potential individuals right now.
Okay.
>> Can we jump
can I jump on if we do it tomorrow,
can we appoint them tomorrow for like, take five minutes and I can jump on?
Eric,
>> I think we have to post the meeting for forty eight hours anyway. Twenty
>> four hours. You could do it tomorrow, but you'd have to do it at 8PM.
No, because you can't publish it in time. Nevermind.
>> It'd have be Can't do it tomorrow. It'd have to be Wednesday, Thursday, or Friday.
>> I think they have a meeting on Wednesday, so they probably need it before Wednesday.
>> No, this issue is related to just two cases
that involve Oh, okay. Well,
>> I think,
yes, I think you're
going to need it for more than two cases
because Georgette is going in for an operation
and will be out of commission for a period of time. So you need to plan on a third
competent
replacement for the BAA.
>> The
way I understood it was that
all of the hearings would be taken care of before she went in for her
procedure.
Maybe.
Yep. And,
>> and there were two issues that were out there that had to be
decided.
There wasn't
as if it was every hearing.
It was only two specific hearings
that had okay. To be
What about Friday?
>> I don't I'm I'm homebound. Whatever you want from me.
Adrian, Friday?
I can make Friday work.
Mhmm. Call a king?
>> Yep. I'll be calling in, but I can make it work.
>> Okay. You
know, I know we try to always have our meetings on time, but is 05:00 work for everybody so we can get it over with?
I'm
>> Jeff Murray, are you with us? I'm not always done working by five, but I will do my best. Of six.
>> Yes. I'm with you. Jeff Murray, can you do Friday or Friday at, like Six. 05:30 or six?
Or what?
>> Is something related
to the Board of Assessment appeals to make an appointment.
>> Yeah,
I guess I'm starting a new job tomorrow, so I, you know, if I can't come, I'll I'll let you know.
Okay.
It's Friday,
>> so let us know. Alright, let's do let's do 6PM on Friday then.
>> Okay, so Eric, can we get that posted and and.
>> Do we wanna do we wanna wait until
maybe Jeff will know tomorrow if he can do six on Friday? If not, can do a different time. That'll still give us forty eight hours.
Sure.
>> So if you just hold the Jeff until Eric
until Jeff reaches out to you tomorrow to clarify time.
Sure.
Okay.
>> Alright,
so.
Does anybody have any other issues that we need to discuss before we move on to item four?
Okay. We're good.
Item four is correspondence. We don't have any. Item five is public speak,
So we'll go through our list.
Joanne Hebert, you are first.
>> All set. Thank you. All right. Diane Choquette.
Also, said is thank you for supporting the seniors,
giving us money for the
community center.
Okay. Victoria Cavanaugh.
I'm good.
>> Okay.
Alright.
I think we're good. Paula, would you like to make a motion to adjourn?
I make a motion to adjourn our meeting.
Seconded.
>> All right. All further
discussion done. All those in favor?
Aye. Aye. Aye.
Alright. Thank you very much, Sherry. Thank you for your time, Eric. Thank for your time. Thanks.
Good night.
Bye.